

## **QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY**

A developer and designer with a diverse background spanning marketing, IT, and creative agency settings. I am passionate about problem solving complex integrations, designing user interface, and data visualization projects. I have professional experience in bringing web design and development projects from concept to production.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## WEB DEVELOPER //

**DENPRO** 

February 2015 - Present | Accokeek, MD / Frederick, MD

Creating websites, web applications, and custom integrations. Development handled in ASP.NET (VB, C#), PHP, JavaScript, HTML and CSS while working with data using MySQL and SQL/Transact-SQL. Outside of development, assisting with implementation and management of SharePoint, CentOS web servers, Windows servers, and VMware ESXi. Design and update of websites using Adobe CC tools.

# WEB DESIGNER + DEVELOPER //

FREELANCE CONSULTANT / CONTRACTOR

May 2014 – February 2015 | Frederick, MD

Produced, updated, and deployed client sites, including: planning, wireframing, design, and development as a contractor. Consulting for SEO / traffic growth, site maintenance, and email (development, tracking, and campaigns).

# WEB PROJECT LEADER //

SHADY GROVE FERTILITY

November 2013 – October 2014 | Rockville, MD

Maintained all technical aspects of the company's WordPress and Drupal sites. Coordinated with content development team to overhaul and improve existing SEO practices. Led design work for web, email, and marketing materials.

#### WEB + GRAPHIC DESIGNER //

SIRE ADVERTISING

July 2011 - November 2013 | Selinsgrove, PA

Headed art direction, webmaster duties, and design for new web projects (2013). As a front-end web designer, garnered the agency recognition through various design awards.

#### **EDUCATION**

## PENNSYLVANIA COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY //

2007 – 2011 Bachelor of Science, Graphic Design Minor in Graphic Communications | (3.8 final GPA)

## BETAMORE ACADEMY //

2014 (Fall) Back-End Web Development

#### **HONORS**

## AMERICAN GRAPHIC DESIGN AWARDS //

GDUSA - 2011, 2012, 2014

## SUMMIT CREATIVE AWARDS //

SUMMIT INTERNATIONAL - 2012, 2013, 2014

#### **SKILLS**

## SOFTWARE + SERVICES //

Visual Studio, Coda, Sublime Text, Atom, Adobe CC / Creative Suite, CodeKit, MAMP / WAMP, Sequel Pro, Navicat, Litmus, Unity Game Engine, MailChimp, ExactTarget, Balsamiq, and others\*

# SKILLS //

Web Development and integrations User Interface Design and Graphic Design Web Content and Project Management IT, Server, and Database Management

#### LANGUAGES //

HTML, CSS, Ruby, PHP, VB/VB.NET, C#, JavaScript, SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis \*

## **LINKS**

## LINKEDIN //

https://www.linkedin.com/in/islane

## GITHUB //

github.com/islane \*\*

## **CERTIFICATIONS + AFFILIATIONS //**

COMPTIA A+

August 2012 – August 2018 (License: QJ03LTG27GV4SF0R)

AIGA - Blue Ridge Chapter 2013 - Present (profile page)

<sup>\*</sup> Please inquire for complete details on my experience regarding software, services, or specific languages.

<sup>\*\*</sup> The majority of my work from 2014–15 is the property of my respective employers and may not be publicly shared, please contact me for samples.